foreign
ER can be represented by a square array
of squares with a side length of 2K Plus
1.
and the nth triangular number can be
represented by a triangular array of
dots where the bottom row has n dots
when we multiply these two numbers
together the product can be represented
by a triangular array of square arrays
as pictured here the number of small
squares in the base is 2K plus 1 times n
but now each Square array that's at the
end of one of the rows has a triangular
array with base length K in the upper
right corner which we can swing around
and drop down into place like this
resulting in an array with a base of 2K
plus 1 times n plus k
if we look carefully this array is
almost triangular but it's just missing
a base K triangular array from the top
therefore we see that 2K plus 1 squared
multiplied by the nth triangular number
T sub n
is given by the 2K plus 1 times n plus K
triangular number minus the K triangular
number T sub K therefore the product of
an odd square and a triangular number is
the difference of two triangular numbers
[Music]